# **Igor Freitas Couto**

Email: igor.fcouto@gmail.com Country of residence: Portugal

**Phone:** +351 913 986 672 **Open to relocation:** Yes

#### **SUMMARY**

Full stack developer with 6 years of experience on .NET technologies and software architecture, in many segments and in companies of different sizes. I've been mainly working in cloud-based environments. Involved and committed to day-to-day work challenges and not only concerned with quality code, but also to deliver software that impacts the company and customers, following agile principles and best practices. Continuously seeks to learn and stay current with emerging technologies and trends in the software development industry.

#### **KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS**

.NET, C#, Architecture design, AWS Cloud Services, ASP.NET, Test Automation (Unit, Acceptance and e2e), Postgres, SQL Server, Redis, Snowflake warehouse, Entity Framework, Dapper, Agile Methodology, Scrum Framework, Git and version control, Docker, CI/CD, Angular, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Redis, Kanban, Azure DevOps, GitLab, Jira, UML, Adobe Photoshop, Blender 3D, Figma, Miro

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

Checkout.com, Portugal Hub – Software Engineer Aug 2023 – Present

# Reports and Reconciliation Team:

As a Software Engineer at Checkout.com, a leading fintech specializing in payment processing, I am a member of the Reports and Reconciliation team. My responsibilities include developing and enhancing features for various services, notably in report generation, client settlements, invoices, and related areas. This work contributes significantly to the company's operational excellence and customer satisfaction.

- Software development in .NET 7
- System design and development
- Experience with Snowflake data warehouse
- Automated unity, functional and e2e testing
- Participating in code review and pair programming
- SCRUM Agile Framework and Jira as project management tool

**Technologies and tools**: .Net 7, Snowflake Database, PostgresDB, Dapper ORM, AWS Services: SSE-KMS, DynamoDB, Kinesis Data Stream, Kinesis Firehose, SQS, SNS, S3, Docker, xUnit, Acceptance Tests, cucumber.js, e2e Tests, Wiremock, Git, GitHub Flow, GitLab, Scrum Framework.

Lambda3 Consulting, Brazil – Software Developer Oct 2020 – Aug 2023

## **Bank Slip Integration Project:**

At a fast-growing fintech, I developed a system offering businesses a new payment option, the Brazilian bank slip (*Boleto*).

- Software development in .NET 7.
- System design and development.
- Experience with distributed SQL database CockroachDB.
- Automated unity, functional and integration testing.
- Participating in code review and pair programming.
- SCRUM Agile Framework and ClickUp as project management tool.

**Technologies and tools**: .Net 6, CockroachDB, Dapper ORM, AWS Lambda Function, AWS SQS, Docker, xUnit, Integration Tests, OAuth 2, xUnit, Wiremock, Git, Git Flow, GitLab, Scrum Framework.

# **Cashback Wallet Project:**

The Wallet system allows businesses to send cashback rewards to customers in their virtual wallets. The cashback is treated exactly as real money and can be redeemed to gain discounts at selected stores.

- Software development in .NET Core 6 with minimal API.
- Web API design and development.
- Experience with distributed SQL database Postgres Citus.
- Azure Cloud infrastructure and services.
- Automated unity, functional and integration testing.
- Participating in code review and pair programming.
- SCRUM Agile Framework and AzureDevops as project management tool.

**Technologies and tools**: .Net 6, Postgres Citus, Entity Framework Core, Database Migrations, Azure Functions, OAuth 2, JWT Authorization Tokens, Docker, nUnit, Wiremock, Git, Azure DevOps, Scrum Framework.

#### Chat System Platform Project:

Elaboration and development of a chat and customer service system for one of Brazil's main retail chains, which provided scale and market gain, especially during the pandemic. The chat system is integrated with WhatsApp Business API from Meta and the company's own mobile app, serving as a conversation aggregator. Seller users can perform customer services and administrative users can mass message potential customers.

- Software development in .NET Core 3.1 and Angular 10.
- Programming and designing database NoSQL MongoDB hosted on Atlas.
- Experience in WebSockets.
- Experience in SAML (SSO).
- AWS Cloud infrastructure and services.
- Automated unity, functional and integration testing.
- SCRUM Agile Framework and Jira as project management tool.
- Participating in code review and pair programming.

**Technologies and tools**: .Net Core 3.1, MongoDB, Redis, Database Migrations, AWS S3, AWS Lambda Functions, AWS SQS, AWS SNS, AWS API Gateway, Angular 10, SPA, HTML, SASS, npm, Docker, nUnit, Selenium, Wiremock, Git, GitLab, Jira, Scrum Framework, Figma.

# Delage Logistics & Supply Chain, Brazil – Systems Analyst Mar 2018 – Oct 2020

# Warehouse Management System (WMS) Platform:

Development of many features for the WMS other auxiliary software for the logistics segment. Created requirements documents, customer visit for demonstration and product deployment in Brazil and Argentina. Architecture and development of integration interfaces with third party systems (ERPs and automation).

- Software development in .NET Core 3.1, .NET Framework, Visual Basic 6, T-SQL, JavaScript, jQuery and Razor.
- Web API Development.
- Programming and designing database SQL Server.
- Experience in writing Stored Procedures, Views, Jobs, etc. (T-SQL).
- Experience in designing and developing Web services (SOAP, REST).
- Experience in deploying on-premises systems.
- Experience in customer support.

**Technologies and tools**: .NET Core 3.1, .NET Framework, Visual Basic 6, T-SQL, SOAP, JavaScript, jQuery, Razor, Git, Git Flow

# Integration with Shuttle and Picking automation hardware:

Development of integration systems to logistics automation machinery in warehouses.

- Windows Service development.
- Experience in writing Stored Procedures (T-SQL).
- Development of complex integrations.
- Deploy on premise systems.
- On-site implementation and support.

**Technologies and tools**: .NET Core 3.1, .NET Framework, Windows Services, Socket TCP, SQL Server, T-SQL, Git.

# Prime System Technical Courses, Brazil – Part Time Teacher Mar 2017 – Mar 2018

As an instructor, I taught Introduction to Programming with C#, Unity Game Engine and creating art assets. This role offered me a unique opportunity to engage with a diverse range of learners, further improving my communication skills and gaining teaching experience.

- Experience in class planning.
- Experience in creating content.

Technologies and tools: .NET Framework, Unity Game Engine, Blender 3D and Adobe Photoshop

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Incomplete Bachelor's degree, Computer Science** Federal University of Juiz de Fora

2011 - 2018

- Member of the junior enterprise, CODE.
- Member of the Computer Graphics, Image and Vision Group.
- Member of the Computer Science Tutorial Education Group, participating in the development of EducAR Quadrics and LocalizAR UFJF apps.
- Led a course for 40 students on 3D modeling.
- Co-authored two academic articles.

# **Technical certificate, Computer Assembly and Repair** Instituto Técnico Profissionalizante do Vale do Rio Preto

2005 - 2006

- Acquired comprehensive knowledge of computer hardware and software, including operating systems.
- Gained proficiency in Linux terminal usage, managing files and system processes.
- Developed skills in troubleshooting and repairing various computer issues, such as hardware malfunctions and software errors.
- Experienced in the assembly and disassembly of computer systems, understanding component compatibility, and system upgrades.

# **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- Self-taught in many technical skills, I love to program in my free time to challenge myself.
- Motivated to explore new ideas.
- Ability to assess a situation and determine the next steps to take.
- Quickly acclimate to different environments.
- Good problem-solving skills and creative thinker.
- Open to new processes and technologies.
- Able to empathize with customers and let them know I care about their issues.

## **ADDITIONAL**

English Certification ETS – TOEFL iBT – Certified 2022, Scored 91 of 120

# Co-author of two academic publications:

(2019) EducAR – Quadrics: A Tool to Aid teaching of Calculus through Augmented

Reality – Brazilian Journal of Computers in Education (Revista Brasileira de Informática na Educação – RBIE), 27(2), 198-217. DOI: 10.5753/RBIE.2019.27.02.198. [Link]

(2017) A Tool to Aid teaching of Calculus through Augmented

Reality – XXVIII Brazilian Symposium on Computers in Education (XXVIII Simpósio Brasileiro De Informática Na Educação - SBIE), DOI: 10.5753/cbie.sbie.2017.595. [Link]

# <u>LinkedIn Profile:</u>

https://linkedin.com/in/igor-fcouto

# GitHub Profile:

https://github.com/igor-couto